disq.us 2009-12-27

# DISQUS | Terms of Service

## Privacy Policy

Disqus.com ("Site") provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection and use of personal information we receive from users who visit the Site and that we receive from users of third party sites which use the Disqus service ("Partner Sites").

### Information Collection on the Site

In the course of using this Site, you may choose to provide us with personally identifiable information. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Information”). Personal Information that we collect from Site users may include, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, email address and home and business postal addresses. Personal Information may also include information you supply concerning your preferences and interests expressed in the course of use of our Site if such information is tied to data that identifies you as an individual. When you visit the Site, our servers automatically record non-personal information based upon your usage of the Site. This information may include, but is not limited to, your computer’s Internet Protocol address, browser type, the web page you were visiting before you came to our Site and information you search for or use on our Site. Like many websites, we also use “cookies” to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use “persistent cookies” to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Site; and we use “session ID cookies” to enable certain features of the Site, to better understand how you interact with the Site and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on the Site. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of our services.

### Information Collection on Partner Sites

Disqus.com may collect information from Partner Sites about you and your usage of the Disqus service on their sites. Such information will not specifically identify you as an individual, but may be used to report anonymous information about your usage of the Partner Site and the Disqus service on that site.

### How We Use Personal Information

Personal Information is only used as described in this Privacy Policy, unless you have consented to another use of your Personal Information. We use Personal Information for the following purposes: (i) internally to provide and improve our Site, services, features and content, (ii) to fulfill requests you may make to us, (iii) to personalize your experience and (iv) to provide you with information and offers from us or third parties that we believe you may find useful or interesting, including newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information on services and products offered by us or third parties. We may permit our vendors to access your Personal Information, but only in connection with services that they perform for us and not to use for their own purposes. We may share or transfer your Personal Information in connection with a merger, sale or reorganization of all or a part of our business. Lastly, we may disclosure your Personal Information if required to do so by process of law, or if necessary in order to investigate fraud, a violation of the Site Terms of Use or in connection with any harm being caused to a third party or their rights.

### How We Use Non-Personal Information

We may use and disclose non-personal information for any number of reasons and with any number of third parties, including in order to monitor and analyze use of the Site and our services and for the Site’s technical administration, to increase our Site’s functionality and user-friendliness, to better tailor it to your needs, to generate and derive useful data and information concerning the interests, characteristics and website use behavior of our users, and to verify that visitors to the Site meet the criteria required to process their requests.

### Information posted in Public Forums

You should be aware that Personal Information which you voluntarily include and transmit online in a publicly assessable blog or otherwise online may be viewed and used by others. We are unable to control such uses of your Personal Information, and by using such services you assume the risk that the Personal Information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties.

### Changing or Deleting Your Information

All registered users may review, update or correct the Personal Information provided in their registration or account profile by changing their “user preferences” in their account. If you choose to opt out entirely, then your account may become deactivated and you will need to re-register should you decide to opt-in again. To delete your account entirely, please email us at help@disqus.com. However, we are not able to remove your Personal Information from the records of any third party who has been provided with your information in compliance with this policy.

### Security

Disqus is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ reasonable measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access. However, there are inherent risks in using the Internet, and we cannot guaranty that your information will be 100% secure.

### Policy Toward Children

This Site is not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at privacy@Disqus.com. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

### Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use Personal Information in a way that materially differs from this policy, we will post such changes here and provide you the opportunity to opt-out of such differing uses. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes.

### United States of America:

Our Site is maintained in the United States of America. By using the Site, you freely and specifically give us your consent to export your personally identifiable information to the USA and to store and use it in the USA as specified in this policy.

### Contact

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at biz@disqus.com

This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 11, 2009
